Littleton, Colo. Ridge Road United Church records, 1958-1993.
Congregational Library & Archives
Littleton, Colo. Ridge Road United Church records, 1958-1993.
RG5513
Congregational Library & Archives
2.69 Cubic Feet
Plans to build a Congregational church in Littleton, Colorado, were begun in 1958. Faith Congregational Church was formally gathered in 1959. The name of the church changed in 1967 to Littleton United Church of Christ. The name of the church changed later to Ridge Road United Church. The church likely closed in 1993. This collection contains administrative records for the Ridge Road United Church in Littleton, Colorado, as well as an extensive collection of scrapbooks. The administrative records contain, primarily, the minutes of church meeting, The scrapbooks document the history of the church, largely through collected bulletins, worship programs, clippings, and photographs.
Ridge Road United Church (Littleton, Colo.)
Faith Congregational Church (Littleton, Colo.)
Littleton United Church of Christ (Littleton, Colo.)
Arrangement
Materials have been arranged in chronological order by start date.
Historical Note
Plans to build a Congregational church along Ridge Road, Littleton, Colorado, were begun in 1958. The name of the newly gathered church was decided in November 1959 by a vote in favor of Faith Congregational Church. The church's first minister was Rev. Gordon Blunt. The name of the church changed in 1967 to Littleton United Church of Christ when the church also decided to join with the United Church of Christ. The name of the church changed again in the 1980s to Ridge Road United Church. The church likely closed in 1993.
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by the Rocky Mountain Conference, August 2021; accession 2021-07.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains administrative records for the Ridge Road United Church in Littleton, Colorado, as well as an extensive collection of scrapbooks documenting the history of the church. The administrative records generally contain meeting minutes, especially those of the church council. The records also contain some lists of baptisms, marriages, and membership. The scrapbooks are extensive and constitute the bulk of the collection. They document the history of the church, largely through collected bulletins, worship programs, clippings, and photographs. There is also a scrapbook documenting the advent of the church Women's Fellowship.
Baptismal records.; Church bulletins.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Marriage records.; Scrapbooks.; Faith Congregational Church (Littleton, Colo.); Littleton (Colo.) -- Church records.; Littleton United Church of Christ (Littleton, Colo.); Ridge Road United Church (Littleton, Colo.)
- Historical scrapbook, 1958 1966; 1958-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Church records, 1959 1966; 1959-1966 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Women's Fellowship scrapbook, 1960 1963; 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Church council meeting minutes, 1966 1968; 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Incorporation certificate, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Historical scrapbook, 1967 1974; 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Church council meeting minutes, 1969 1978; 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newsletter, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Historical scrapbook, 1975 1976; 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Historical scrapbook, 1977 1978; 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Historical scrapbook, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Historical scrapbook, 1981 1982; 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Historical scrapbook, 1983 1984; 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Historical scrapbook, 1985 1986; 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Church council meeting minutes, 1985 1988; 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Church records, 1990 1993; 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)